Guide to the Browning Photograph Collection 1918-1952 (bulk, 1920-1938) PR 9
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Photographs
  - Television and Radio
    - Television Broadcasting -- Control room and operator at CBS (2), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 199)
    - Television Broadcasting -- Phillips, Sandra, broadcasting at CBS (2), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 199)
    - Television Broadcasting -- Television cameras, undated (Offsite-box 2, Folder 199)
  - Theaters
    Theaters includes a few grand Broadway theaters of the era, but focuses heavily on the great movie palaces of the late 1920s and the 1930s, such as the Earl Carroll and the RKO Roxy Theatre. A heavy focus on interiors, and especially art-deco design elements, is evident. Also included are some views of burlesque and less legitimate venues, such as the Salon des Arts. Several theaters in this subseries were heavily documented by Browning, probably working on commission; some construction progress views are included.
    - Ambassador Theatre, interiors (2), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 200)
    - Astor Theatre, marquee for Eskimo and New Moon, 1933 (Offsite-box 20, Folder 200)
    - Avon Theatre, interior, detail of controls, undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 200)
    - Beacon Theatre, interiors and exteriors, undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 201)
    - Biltmore Theatre, interiors (2), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 201)
    - Brooklyn Paramount Theatre, interiors (5), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 201)
    - Carlton Theatre, interiors and exteriors (Brooklyn) (8), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 202)
    - Cameo Theatre, ticket booth and entrance, undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 202)
    - Century Theatre and view of Central Park West at 61st St., [1925] (Offsite-box 20, Folder 202)
    - Criterion Theatre, actor Neil Hamilton and others in entrance, undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 202)
    - undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 203)
    - Earl Carroll Theatre, interiors and exteriors - including during construction (46), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 203-205)
    - Embassy Theatre, interiors (Port Chester, NY) (4), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 206)
    - Forrest Theatre, interiors (3), undated (Offsite-box 20, Folder 206)
    - George M. Cohan's Theatre, entrance, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 206)
    - Imperial Theatre, interiors (3), undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 207)
    - Jolson's 59th Street Theatre, interiors (3), [1921-1930] (Offsite-box 21, Folder 207)
    - Loew's Coney Island Theatre, interior, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 207)
    - Loew's Grand (The Bronx), undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 207)
    - Loew's Inwood, interiors (9), undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 207)
    - Madison Square Garden, interiors and exteriors (1892 and 1925 buildings) (7), undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 208)
    - Mansfield Thatre, interior, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 208)
    - Oasis Theatre, interiors (4), undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 209)
    - Palace Theatre, entrance (2), undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 209)
    - Paramount Theatre, Broadway at 44th St., interiors and exterior (6), 1926, undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 210)
    - RKO Roxy Theatre, interiors and exteriors (65), undated (Offsite-box 21, Folder 211-213)
    - Republic Theatre (Burlesque), marquee (2), [1932] (Offsite-box 21, Folder 214)
    - Salon des Arts, undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 215)
    - Sam H. Harris Theatre, interior, signs for The Singing Fool, [1929] (Offsite-box 22, Folder 215)
    - Thalia Theatre, Broadway and 95th St., interiors and exterior (7), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 215)
    - Theatre Guild, interior, undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 215)
    - Trans-Lux Theatre, Broadway and 49th-50th St. (3), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 216)
    - Valencia Theatre, interiors and exteriors (Jamaica, Queens) (6), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 216)
    - Theater sign switchboxes (4), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 217)
    - Unidentified theatre interiors (5), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 218)
  - Tourists
    Tourists consists of photographs of crowds looking through telescopes, gathered on the streets, and standing on viewing platforms.
    - Views of tourists (11), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 219)
  - Transportation
    Transportation contains a variety of views of public transportation in the New York area, including buses, elevated railroads, railroad stations, street railroads, and subway station entrances. Especially notable are Browning's photographs of Grand Central Terminal and McKim, Mead & White's Pennsylvania Station.
    - Buses (4), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 220)
    - Elevated railroads (4), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 221)
    - Railroad stations -- Grand Central Terminal, interiors and exteriors (14), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 222)
    - Railroad Stations -- Morrisania Station (Bronx) (3), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 222)
    - Railroad stations -- Pennsylvania Station, interiors and exteriors (6), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 222)
    - Street railroads (streetcars) (4), undated (Offsite-box 22, Folder 223)
    - Subway station entrances (4), 1933 (Offsite-box 22, Folder 224)
  - Utilities
    Utilities consists of photographs of power lines, power plants, electric transformers, ash shoots, and gas tanks. Included are Consolidated Edison facilities, but most of the photographs in this series do not bear specific descriptions.
    - Utilities (20), undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 225)
  - Winter Views
    Winter Views depict a snow-covered Central Park framed by the towers of Fifth Avenue and Central Park South and West. They are mostly quiet, unpopulated landscapes; the few people in view are a man and child holding hands as they walk down a snowy path, a group of men gazing at the scenery from a horse-drawn carriage, and distant figures walking along a white-on-white horizon. Also included are a few night views that contrast the gleaming snow against a darkened sky.
    - Central Park (23), undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 226)
    - Times Square, Broadway (6), 1922, [1929-1930] (Offsite-box 23, Folder 227)
    - Unidentified (8), undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 228)
  - Miscellaneous and Unidentified
    Miscellaneous and Unidentified Views includes a traffic light, unidentified gravestones, unidentified landscapes and buildings, a man exhaling smoke profiled in a doorway, and some unidentified architectural details.
    - Miscellaneous and Unidentified (14), undated (Offsite-box 23, Folder 229)
- Series II. Documents
  Series II dates from consists of the contents of a scrapbook compiled by Irving Browning including ephemera and correspondence relating to Browning's career as a photographer and cinematographer. During processing, items were removed from acidic scrapbook pages, and the former page number was written on the verso of each item so that the original arrangement could be reconstructed if necessary. Materials are arranged alphabetically by format or genre, as described below.
  Advertisements includes posters for events in which Irving Browning was involved, including an exhibition of his photographs at the First Annual Motion Picture and Costume Ball of the Film and Photo League on April 27th, 1934 and speaking engagements at DeWitt Clinton High School and the Film and Photo League.
  Clippings includes items related to Irving Browning's exhibitions, a clipping of his published photograph of an elevated railroad, and a news photograph of Browning directing child actors in a film.
  Correspondence includes several letters from Browning's colleague Lars Moën, regarding experiments with color film, a few letters regarding membership in professional societies such as the American Television Society and the Society of Motion Picture Engineers, as well as correspondence from the Film and Photo League, the manager of The Film Daily, Carl Louis Gregory, and S. Barret McCormick of RKO Radio Pictures. Also included is a correspondence from RKO Radio concerning details of construction and equipment for the RKO Roxy Theatre.
  Identification Cards and Membership Cards are primarily from professional organizations and conferences in the 1940s and 1950s. These include several Universal Newsreel Field Cameraman identification cards (which include most of the few photographs of Irving Browning in this collection), union membership cards for the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators, a New York State drivers license from 1946, and other miscellaneous cards.
  Pamphlets includes a Code of Ethics for the Society of Photographic Illustrators and an pamphlet about the New Film Alliance. Ribbons includes several exhibitor's ribbons from the Third Annual Exhibit of Professional Photography held in Rochester, New York. Tickets and a pass for the 1940 New York World's Fair are also included in this series. Photocopies of the original scrapbook pages are also in this series.
  - Advertisements, 1934, 1937, undated (Offsite-box 24, Folder 230)
    See also: Box 25, Folder 240
  - Clippings, 1928-1941 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 231)
  - Correspondence, 1918-1944 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 232)
  - Identification cards, 1942-1952, undated (Offsite-box 24, Folder 233)
  - Membership cards, 1939-1947 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - Pamphlets, undated (Offsite-box 24, Folder 235)
  - Ribbons [emphemera], from the Third Annual Exhibition of Professional Photography at the Rochester Athenaeum and Mechanics Institute, Rochester, NY, 1936 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 236)
  - Tickets and pass to the New York World's Fair 1940 (Offsite-box 24, Folder 237)
  - Photocopies of original scrapbook pages, undated (Offsite-box 24, Folder 238)
  - Scrapbook cover, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 239)
  - Advertisements, oversize, undated (Offsite-box 25, Folder 240)
- From Series I. Photographs
  - Curator's reserves -- duplicates, undated (Offsite-box 26, Offsite-box 27)